Inventory of the Papers of the Person Family, 1872-2002
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
A Guide to the Papers of the Person Family 1872-2002
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
200.56; 2006.44
Form of material and dates: Papers, 1872-2002, of the Person family.
William L. Person, Jr.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to all researchers.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1872-2002, of the person family including account book of both Charles Person and William Person, Sr. and other account books and diaries; papers having to do with family life in the city of Williamsburg in the early-to-mid 1900s; pictures, mainly of the Person family, which also show the lifestyle of the early-to-mid 1900s; artifacts, including fans and a Williamsburg Laundry thermometer and a charcoal drawing of a residence.
Contents List
- 1886-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  chronological
  - 1886-1923, 582 pp. MsV. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Account book of Charles J. Person and William L. Person, Sr., Williamsburg, Va., from C.J. Person Jeweler and Person Motor Corp.
  - 1872-1878., 123 pp. MsV. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Unidentified Account Book.
  - 1915-1922., 166 pp. MsV. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Diary of Alice Person, Williamsburg, Va.
  - 1928-1930., 184 pp. MsV. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Account Book of Person Motor Corp., Williamsburg, Va.
- 1918-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1-29)
  - July 8, 1993., Cy of ALS and PDS. 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Letter to William L. Person, Jr., Williamsburg, Va., from Cotesworth Lewis. Thanks Person for a check for 100 dollars from his mother's estate, but returns it; Lewis could never accept the money because Person's mother was too dear a friend.
  - Sept[ember] 29, 1930., ALS. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Letter to G.P. Coleman, Williamsburg, Va., from Celine Burrett, Rockford, Il. Burrett asks Coleman, the librarian in Williamsburg, to solve a dispute on what type of car Mr. Charles Person owned, as it was the first car in Williamsburg. Includes a return envelope.
  - Sept[ember] 25, 1922., PM. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Telegram to Alice Person, Williamsburg, Va., from D. E. McQuilken, Roanoke, Va. McQuilken asks whether Person is coming back to Roanoke and if they should appoint another teacher.
  - September 20, 1920-June 9, 1955, n.d., TCs and TCS. 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Assorted printed greeting cards. Marriage announcements for Frances May Person and Muriel Person, daughters of Charles J. Person, and Florence May Person, sister of Charles J. Person. Also included are notices of graduation for Williamsburg High School and the Matthew Whaley School; a Valentine Card from Flora and Marion Bzarth; a note announcing the opening of the law office of William L. Person, Jr.
  - December 6, 1918-n.d., See Box VI. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Invitations to various events at the College of William and Mary. Invitation to a Military Ball commemorating the end of World War I; a handwritten invitation to an event the German Club had in the College Gymnasium; an invitation to meet the Governor and his wife. AC and TCs. 3 items. Will be transferred to University Archives.
  - 1985., See box VI. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Speech made by William L. Person, Jr., naming Jim Seu the Restaurateur of the Year, as recognized by the Order of the White Jacket. Also includes an agenda for the meeting during which the speech was made. TMs and PM. 2 items.
  - June 14, 2002., TMs and PMs. 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Speech given by William L. Person on the retirement of Mayor Vernon M. Geddy, Jr. Includes programs for the tribute to Mayor Geddy.
  - n.d., PMs. 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Postcards, depicting the cruise ship "Jamestown" on the James River and Person Motor Corp.
  - April 16, 1928., PDsS and TDS. 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Deed of Sale and Policy of Title insurance for Lot 6, Block E on College Terrace, sold by the College of William and Mary to Hortense S. Person.
  - November 27, 1921-January 30, 1928., PDsS. 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Certificates of stock in Person Motor Corporation issued to William L. Person, Sr.
  - January 31, 1990., Cy of TDS. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Oath and certificate appointing William L. Person, Jr. a Judge of the Ninth Judicial Circuit of Virginia.
  - [April] 9, 1919., TD. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Bill to C[harles] J. Person from J.R. Wood Diamond Cutters.
  - 1942-1943., PVs. 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    World War II ration books and a military insignia identification booklet.
  - May 29-31, 1922., Mss. 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Autograph pages from Alice Person's fellow graduates from the College of William and Mary.
  - May 2, 1919., PM. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Program for the Banquet of the Class of 1922, with Governor Hugh Dorsey of Georgia in attendance.
  - November 21, 1921, November 9, 1923., PMs. 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Programs for dinner banquets given by Delta Phi Kappa fraternity, which became Pi Beta Phi sorority in 1925.
  - June 10, 1956., PM. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Program for the Commencement Exercises of the College of William and Mary.
  - June 7, 1922, June 10, 1956., PMs. 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Programs for the commencement exercises of the College of William and Mary.
  - March 23, 1918-December 9,1949, n.d., PMs. 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Playbills for plays in the Williamsburg community which either feature or were attended by a member of the Person family. They Include "Isle of Jewels", "A Night at an Inn", a band concert, "The Pied Piper of Hamelin", which includes a newspaper clipping, "Lombardi Ltd.", and "The Microbe of Love."
  - March 29, 1919-March 14, 1947., PMs. 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Playbills for plays at the College of William and Mary, seen by either Alice Person or William L. Person, Jr. Some plays include Vernon Geddy as an actor.
  - July 4, 1922., PM. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Program for the "Community Celebration and John Marshall Pageant," held on the campus of the College of William and Mary. Event includes a play of John Marshall's life, sporting events, prizes, and a humorous play.
  - n.d., PMs. 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Assorted cards from Person Motors, William L. Person, Jr.'s basketball season ticket for the Matthew Whaley School basketball team, William L. Person, Jr.'s Cub Scout and Boy Scout membership cards.
  - [April 25] 1922., PM. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Baseball schedule of the College of William and Mary baseball team from 1922, with partial results. Also included are cartoons of the members of the team.
  - 1954-1955., PV. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Telephone directory for the cities of Williamsburg, Lee Hall, Seaford, and Yorktown.
  - n.d., PV. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Advertisement and admissions pamphlet about the College published during the presidency of Lyon Gardner Tyler.
  - April 11, 1924-April 26, 1925., PMs. 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Programs and songbook for the Girls' Reserve of the YWCA.
  - July 23, 1930., XCy of PM. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Menu and sign-in from a meeting of the Pulaski Club.
  - 1955., TM. 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Vespers Service for the Graduating Class of 1955 [of the College of William and Mary?].
  - n.d., PMs. 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Miscellaneous papers, including a newspaper notice of William L. Person, Jr.'s 3rd birthday, a Bible test, a picture of an unidentified building, train tickets, an Auction Score Sheet, and a tag with "Miss Person" written on it.
- 1928-2002; n.d. (Box 3, Folder 30-49)
  Newspapers and Photographs.
  - (Box 3, Folder 30-40)
    - n.d., NwsCl. 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Newport News ferry schedule.
    - March 29, 1928., XCy of NwsCl. 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Obituary in the Daily Press for Charles J. Person.
    - April 2, 1937-April 1, 1938., NwsCls and XCy of NwsCl. 4 items. (Box 3, Folder 32)
      Newspaper clippings involving William L. Person, Sr, including a picture with him and Grace Moore.
    - May 21, 1997., NwsCl. 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Newspaper section about the 100th anniversary of the Crestar Bank, with a mention of William L. Person, Jr.
    - June 15, 2002., NwsCl. 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Newspaper clipping about the tribute to Vernon Geddy, with a quote by William L. Person, Jr.
    - October 22, [193?]-[June] 29, 2002., NwsCls. 7 items. (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Reflections on the ways that Williamsburg has changed since the restoration of the colonial district; articles mention various members of the Person family.
    - August 8, 1982-Nov[ember] 13, 1999, n.d., NwsCls and XCy of NwsCl. 6 items. (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Newspaper clippings regarding William L. Person, Jr.'s career as a judge.
    - March 1978-Sept[ember] 25, 1997., NwsCls and PM. 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Information about Williamsburg social clubs, including the Kiwanis club and the informal Businessmen's club, known as the Exalted Order of the Asp.
    - August 1989., Nws. 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Alumni Gazette of the College of William and Mary, with a cover picture and article of William L. Person, Jr.
    - October 3, 1999., Nws. 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Newsprint magazine for the Occasion for the Arts.
    - n.d., Nws. 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Fake newspaper which doubles as a program for the play "Their Honor the Mayor."
  - (Box 3, Folder 41-49)
    - 20 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 5/8", black and white, front view of the Person Motor Corporation filling station.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 5/8", black and white, front view of the Person Motor Corporation building, with an unidentified man walking inside the open door.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 5/8", black and white, front view of the Person Motor Corporation building, with an air pump on the left side of the picture.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 5/8", black and white, rear view of the Person Motor Corporation building, with an unidentified man working on a car with its hood up.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 5/8", black and white, side view of the Person Motor Corporation building, with an unidentified man standing by a window, talking to someone inside.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 5/8", black and white, front view of the Person Motor Corporation building, with three cars and a bicycle parked in front of the building.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 2 items. Ps. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 2 5/8" x 4 1/2", black and white, front view of two mechanics and a toddler, Bert Score, Billy, and Willy Lawson, outside of the Person Motor Corporation building.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 5" x 3 1/2", black and white, font view of the Person Ford dealership.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 5" x 3 1/2", black and white, front view of the Person Ford dealership, featuring one car in the foreground.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 5" x 3 1/2", black and white, front view of the Person Ford dealership, featuring one car in the foreground, picture taken from across the street.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 5" x 3 1/2", black and white, rear view of the Person Ford dealership, showing cars in various states of repair.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 5" x 4", black and white, front view of three new cars inside a dealership.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 2 items. Ps. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 7" x 5", black and white, side view of the service and advertising vehicles for the Person Motor Corporation.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 7" x 5", black and white, front view of Person's Service Center, with all of the employees lined up in front.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of unidentified men in suits, members of the Person Motor Corporation.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of the Person Motor Corporation Service Center, picture taken from across the street.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of a man, possible William L. Person, Sr., giving keys to the Person Motor Corp Welcome Wagon and a basket to an elderly woman.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. Oct[ober] [19]61., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of a large group of people standing in front of Person Ford Inc. with children.
      - Pictures of the Person Motor Corporation. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of the inside of the Person Motor Corporation, with a display of an engine in the center.
    - Pictures of William L. Person, Sr., 4 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Sr. March, 1958., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of J.B. Cowles, T.N.P. Cutler, Col. O.G. Pitz, L.R. O'Hara, W[illiam] L. Person[, Sr.], R.A. Duncan, A.E. Kendrew, and Fraser Neiman, as members of the Advance Campaign Committee for the Community Hospital fund.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Sr. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 9 1/2" x 7 1/2", black and white, front view of the Board of Directors of the Peninsula Band and Trust Company, of which William L. Person, Sr., Alvin Duke Chandler, Davis Y. Paschall, and Vernon Geddy.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Sr. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of men in business suits, with William L. Person, Sr. the second person from the left in the second row.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Sr. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of three men in suits, with William L. Person, Sr. in the center.
    - Pictures of William L. Person, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Jr. [1951?]., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 7" x 5", black and white, front view of the Matthew Whaley Student Council, with William L. Person, Jr. Names of the members are written on the back.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Jr. 1958., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4" x 3 1/4", black and white, front view of William L. Person, Jr., giving a tour boat narration at Jamestown.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Jr. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 5" x 3 1/2", color, front view of William L. Person, Jr., with two unidentified people.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Jr. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 7" x 5", black and white, front view of William L. Person, Jr., at a party, with three other unidentified people.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Jr. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of the Matthew Whaley School Marching Band, positioned on the front steps of the school.
      - Pictures of William L. Person, Jr. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 8", black and white, front view of a class of young boys and their teachers on the front steps of the Matthew Whaley School. Mounted on cardboard.
    - Pictures of the Person family. (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Pictures of the Person family. June 1925., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 2 1/2" x 3 1/2", black and white, front view of members of the faculty of the Matthew Whaley School, including Alice Person.
      - Pictures of the Person family. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 3 3/4" x 3 3/4", black and white, front view of C.J. Person Jeweler. Mounted.
      - Pictures of the Person family. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 5" x 4", black and white, front view of a group of girls dressed in Indian costumes, including Alice Person.
      - Pictures of the Person family. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 7" x 5", black and white, front view of a bandstand era big band, including Waverly Person.
      - Pictures of the Person family. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 8" x 10", black and white, front view of Emily G. Person getting out of a horse drawn carriage, in front of the Governor's Mansion, with a Peninsula Lines bus in the background.
    - Other Identified People. (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Other Identified People. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 1/2". black and white, front view of Dr. Bell, the father of Baxter Bell.
      - Other Identified People. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print, 3 1/2" x 3 1/2", black and white, front view of Richard Cottingham, John Eubank, and Bill Bowry sitting on a metal box.
      - Other Identified People. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Mounted professional print. 4 1/8" x 6 1/2", black and white, front view of Lucy Vaiden.
      - Other Identified People. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 7" x 5", black and white, front view of the Post 39 Baseball team.
    - Pictures of buildings. (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Pictures of buildings. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/4" x 5 1/4", black and white, front view of the Powder Magazine in Williamsburg, from before the restoration. There is a modern building in the background, and a low fence around the Magazine.
      - Pictures of buildings. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Mounted professional print. 9" x 7", black and white, front view of Bruton Parish Church, as seen from across Duke of Gloucester Street, with ivy completely covering one side.
      - Pictures of buildings. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Mounted professional print. 9" x 7", black and white, front view of the altar of Bruton Parish Church, with the pulpit on the left and the baptismal font in the center.
    - Pictures relating to the College of William and Mary. (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Pictures relating to the College of William and Mary. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 3 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, side view of Commencement at the College of William and Mary. Even is taking place in the Wren Yard, and is being taped for television.
      - Pictures relating to the College of William and Mary. n.d., 1 item. Pst. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photostat of a yearbook page. 8" x 10", black and white, view of the members of Kappa Sigma Fraternity.
      - Pictures relating to the College of William and Mary. n.d., 1 item. Pst. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photostat of a yearbook page. 10" x 8", black and white, view of the members of the Nu Chapter of Kappa Sigma Fraternity.
    - Unidentified Pictures. (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 3 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, front view of a group of young children standing in front of the porch of a white house.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 3 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, front view of a street with cars traveling in both directions, with a median in the middle and American flags on the telephone poles.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, front view of two young boys dressed as cowboys, with a younger child in a baby seat, and a young dog.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, front view of a group of men sitting around a table playing cards.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 2 1/2" x 4 1/2", black and white, front view of two boys dressed as cowboys, with one pointing a toy gun at the camera.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, side view of a group of men sitting around a table and playing cards.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, front view of a group of young boys standing together on a baseball field.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, front view of three dressed up young boys, sitting on a brick wall.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 3/4" x 2 7/8", black and white, front view of a group of young boys and girls standing on playthings outside, with an adult present.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 3 1/4" x 5 1/4", black and white, front view of 7 boys sitting on brick stairs, one holding a football, and an adult mail sitting with them.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 7" x 5", black and white, front view of a large group of men from the Fisk Corporation standing in front of the Fort Magruder Dining Room.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 3 items. Ps. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 10" x 7", black and white, front view of a large group of young adults both sitting and standing on the steps of a building[Ewell Hall?]. On the reverse of this picture are two other pictures, one of a woman standing on a porch, and another of three women sitting in a doorway.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 5 items. Ps. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Mounted photographic prints. 10" x 7", black and white. Front side has four pictures of a parade, which includes two of a car advertising Person Motor Corp., one of a horse drawn carriage, and the last of a marching band. The reverse side has one picture, a close up of the carriage from the other side.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Photographic print. 4 1/2" x 2 1/2", black and white, front view of wreckage along a train tack, possibly from a wrecked train car.
      - Unidentified Pictures. n.d., 1 item. P. (Box 3, Folder 3)